<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "manual.ent">
<!ENTITY PRODUCT "Documentation">
<!ENTITY BOOKID "manual">
<!ENTITY YEAR "2015">
<!ENTITY HOLDER "Eneo Tecnología S.L. |">
]>
<chapter>
	<title>Configuration and registration of IPS sensors</title>
	<para>After installation, start the configuration process of the sensors. There are basically two parts: network configuration and registration in Horama (Managers). The registration of the sensors in the Manager involves completion of the installation process of the redBorder IPS solution in the appliance.</para>
	<para> After automatic reboot, you will have access to the following screen:</para>
	<mediaobject>
		<imageobject>
			<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ips-install/16.png"/>
		</imageobject>
	</mediaobject>
	<para>Below perform the following:</para>
    <itemizedlist mark="bullet">
		<listitem>
			<para>Login</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>Password</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>Command rb_sysconf</para>
		</listitem>
	</itemizedlist>	
	<para>This process is identical to that discussed in the completion process of the <emphasis role="bold">Installation Configuration Assistant Manager.</emphasis></para>
	<para>You can refer to this information in <emphasis role="bold">Chapter 3, Section 3.1. Finishing Installation Configuration Assistant Manager.</emphasis></para>
	 <para>In this section there is a detailed explanation of the steps to  follow to complete the process and launch the setup menu of the IPS sensors.</para>
	<mediaobject>
		<imageobject>
			<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ips-install/17.png"/>
	    </imageobject>
	</mediaobject>
	<section>
		<title>Setup Menu IPS sensors</title>
		<para>Execute the command <literal>rb_sysconf</literal> to access the menu <emphasis role="bold"> Setting redBorder.</emphasis></para>
		<para>This menu contains 5 options:</para>
		<orderedlist numeration="arabic">
			<listitem>
				<para><literal>System Configuration:</literal>From this option you can define and modify some basic system settings such as name, hour, keyboard layout, etc.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><literal>Network Configuration:</literal> this is the option from which  all the network settings for the proper installation of the solution are made.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><literal>Passwords:</literal> access this option if you want to change your passwords.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><literal>Backup System:</literal> make a backup of the configuration</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><literal>Update rules from Manager:</literal> Select this option to force Download Manager rules. (Optional).</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><literal>quit:</literal> Quit.</para>
			</listitem>
		</orderedlist>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ips-install/18.png"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title> Steps for configuring IPS sensors</title>
		<para>In order for the redBorder IPS solution to work properly, it is necessary to first put the sensors in the network.To do this, the user will have to perform the network configuration, selecting <literal>Network Configuration</literal> by inserting the number <keycap>2</keycap>once you have accessed the redBorder configuration wizard.</para>
		<para>Until you have done this configuration, you can not proceed with registration of the sensors in the Manager.</para>
		<para>These are the steps to follow to install the IPS sensors:</para>
		<orderedlist numeration="arabic">
			<listitem>
				<para>Network Configuration Management:</para>
				<para>a) Creation of bonding and assigning interface management.</para>
				<para>b) Setting segments or network interfaces which are to be placed sensors.</para>	
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>DNS Settings and Domain Settings</para>
			</listitem>
		</orderedlist>
		<note>
			<title>Note</title>
			<para>The order indicated in this installation manual is what is considered optimal.</para>
		</note>
		<warning>
			<title>Caution</title>
			<para>If the system is installed on a real computer with more than one network card, the user must choose the bonding management.</para>
		</warning>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Management Network Configuration: creation of bonding and assignment of interface management</title>
		<para>Select the <literal>Network Configuration</literal> option by selecting <keycap>2</keycap> and pressing <keycap>Enter.</keycap></para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ips-install/18.png"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>If the system recognizes the interfaces with a <emphasis>bypass</emphasis> these will automatically be assigned to the segments.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ips-install/19.png"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>Then the following actions will be taken to ensure that the network sensor is configured correctly:</para>
		<itemizedlist mark="bullet">
			<listitem>
				<para>Creating a bonding: (maximum 4 bonds).</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Selecting and assigning ports to bonding.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Configuration interface management for bondings created.</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<para>For the selection of ports, a list will be displayed with detailed and valuable information, which will help the administrator to decide which ports to assign to the bonding.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ips-install/20.png"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
		<note>
			<title>Note</title>
			<para>Selecting Presets: <keycap>Enter</keycap></para>
		</note>
		<section>
			<title>Creating a new bonding and assignment of port</title>
			<para>To illustrate this process you will create a bonding (bond0) and assign 2 ports.</para>
			<para>Select the <keycap>n</keycap> option on the lateral submenu right of the screen.</para>
			<para>Once you have reviewed the ports available, select the one you want to assign to bonding, as it appears at the bottom of the previous screen.</para>
			<para>Enter the port number in the line<literal>Insert bonding first port [0]: _</literal></para>
			<para>The number in brackets<literal>[]</literal>  is what defines the system default. To select this number, press <keycap>Enter</keycap>.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ips-install/21.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>The port selected option disappears from the available ports.</para>
			<note>
				<title>Note</title>
				<para>The system only allows the creation of up to 4 bonds: (0-3).</para>
			</note>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title> Add a new port bonding</title>
			<para>The system will ask the following:  <literal>Insert second port (y/N):_</literal></para>
			<para>The option selected by default is capitalized. Remember that if you DO NOT want to add a new port just have to press the <keycap>Enter</keycap> key.</para>
			<para>If you want to insert a new port, type <keycap>y</keycap>.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ips-install/21.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>Enter the port number on the second line<literal>Insert bonding second port [1]: _</literal></para>
			<para>The number in brackets <literal>[]</literal>  is the defining default system. To select this number, press <keycap>Enter</keycap>.</para>			
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Network configuration of bonding</title>
			<para>Once you have made the assignment of the second port to the new bonding (bond0), the system will prompt you to enter the following data:</para>
			<itemizedlist mark="bullet">
				<listitem>
					<para>IP Address</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Netmask</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Gateway</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Routes</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<para>If your computer uses DHCP, you will be assigned an IP address by default. Press <keycap>Enter</keycap>  to select the IP, mask and gateway assigned by the system. Otherwise, manually enter these values. </para>
			<para>The system also gives a default route for the bonding created.</para>
			<para>To insert a path manually, select <keycap>y</keycap> in the line<literal> Insert a route for this bonding (y/N)?:_</literal></para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ips-install/25.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>Once this process has been finished a display message will appear that says <literal>Bonding 0 created successfully.</literal></para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ips-install/26.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Finish the process of creating the bonding</title>
			<para>Before applying changes and finalizing the process of creating the bonding, the system will display a table that contained the new bonding created (bond0) along with the ports that have been assigned, IP and Mask and manually assigned route or default. </para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ips-install/23.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>		
			<para><emphasis role="bold">Apply Changes</emphasis></para>
			<para>In order for modifications to be saved, you must perform the action to implement changes by selecting <keycap>a.</keycap></para>
			<para>At any time you can delete the created bonds by selecting <literal>delete bonding</literal>  entering the letter <keycap>d.</keycap></para>
			<para> To return to the main menu network configuration, select the <literal>quit</literal>  option with the letter <keycap>q.</keycap></para>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Configuring DNS and domain settings</title>
		<para>In the Network Configuration menu you will find options <literal>DNS and domain settings.</literal> To begin the process, select option <keycap>2.</keycap></para>
		<para>To complete the settings correctly, the user must enter:</para>
		<itemizedlist mark="bullet">
			<listitem>
				<para>  Domain Name</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Primary DNS Address</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Secondary DNS Address (optional)</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<para> After entering this information, the system will prompt that it has  correctly applied this configuration.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ips-install/28.png"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>To finish the  process, it is not necessary to apply changes. To return to Network Settings  in the main menu select option <literal>quit</literal> by entering the letter <keycap>q</keycap>.</para>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Configuring network segments</title>
		<para>In the Network Settings menu select the option <literal>Segment settings</literal> by entering the number <keycap>3</keycap>.</para>
		<para>This screen shows the number of segments that have been created, the ports assigned to each segment and if these have no support or bypass.</para>
		<para>You will find the following submenu: </para>
		<itemizedlist mark="bullet">
			<listitem>
				<para><keycap>f)</keycap> <literal>force bypass autoassign:</literal>force the automatic assignment of port with bypass.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><keycap>n)</keycap> <literal>new segment:</literal>select to create a new segment.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><keycap>d)</keycap> <literal>delete segment:</literal>delete a segment.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><keycap>q)</keycap> <literal>quit:</literal>exit</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<para>To begin creating a <literal>new segment</literal> select the option segment inserting the letter<keycap>n</keycap>.</para>
		<para>The process of creating segments comprises the following actions:</para>
		<orderedlist numeration="arabic">
			<listitem>
				<para>Auto-assign interfaces to bypass segments (optional) type.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Creation of a segment: (maximum 16 segments).</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para> Selection and assignment of ports to the segment.</para>
			</listitem>
		</orderedlist>
		<para> For the selection of ports, a list will be displayed with detailed and valuable information, which will help the administrator to decide which segments will be created.</para>
		<section>
			<title>Assigning interfaces to bypass segments</title>
			<para>If the system detects bypass interfaces, these are automatically assigned to segments when entering the menu Network Settings.</para>
			<para>There are also two modes of assignment of ports or interfaces to bypass segments:</para>
			<itemizedlist mark="bullet">
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold"> Forcing bypass auto-assign: </emphasis> select option <literal>Force bypass auto assign</literal>  in the Segments Setting menu, by pressing the letter <keycap>f.</keycap></para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Manual assignment:</emphasis> selecting ports with bypass from the available ports listed will be displayed in the process of creating segments.</para>				
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ips-install/32.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ips-install/31.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Creating a new segment and assignment of port</title>
			<para>To illustrate this process we will create a segment (segment 0) and will assign 2 ports. </para>
			<para>To begin the process of creating the segment, select <keycap>n</keycap> in the lateral submenu right of the screen.</para>
			<para>Once you have reviewed the ports available, select the one you want to assign to the segment as it appears at the bottom of the previous screen.</para>
			<para>Enter the number that will give the segment on the line <literal>Insert segment number (0-15) [0]:_</literal></para>
			<para>The number in brackets <literal>[]</literal> is the one that defines the system default. To select this number, press <keycap>Enter</keycap>.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ips-install/29.png"/>
				</imageobject>
		    </mediaobject>
		    <para>The port previously assigned to the segment will disappear from the list of available ports. </para>
		    <note>
				<title>Note</title>
				<para>The system only allows the creation of up to 16 segments (0-15).</para>
		    </note>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Add a second port segment</title>
			<para>Once the first port is assigned to the segment, the system will make it possible to assign a second port to the segment: <literal>Assign second port to the segment (Y/n):_</literal></para>
			<para>The option that is predetermined by default is capitalized.</para>
			<para>Remember that if you want to assign a new port you only have to press the <keycap>Enter</keycap> key.</para>
			<para> If you don’t want to assign a new port, type<keycap>n</keycap>. Once you have reviewed the ports that are available, select the one you would like to assign to a segment as shown at the bottom margin of the previous screen.</para>
			<para> Enter the port number in the line <literal>Insert segment second port [3]: _</literal></para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ips-install/30.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>Once you have assigned the two ports to a segment, the system will let you know that the segment has been created properly <literal>Segment 0 created successfully.</literal></para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ips-install/31.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Finish the process of creating segments</title>
			<para>Before applying changes and finalizing the process of creating the segment, a screen will be displayed with a list containing the following elements:</para>
			<itemizedlist mark="bullet">
				<listitem>
					<para>Segments</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Ports assigned to the segment</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Whether or not you have bypass interfaces</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ips-install/34.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>		
			<para><emphasis role="bold">Apply Changes</emphasis></para>
			<para>In order for modifications to remain saved you must perform the action to apply changes by selecting option <keycap>a.</keycap></para>
			<para>You can delete the created segments at any time by entering the letter <literal>delete segment</literal>, insertando la letra <keycap>d.</keycap></para>
			<para> To return to Network Settings in the main menu, select the <literal>quit</literal> option by entering <keycap>q.</keycap></para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ips-install/35.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>	
		</section>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Appliances managed via IPMI</title>
		<para>In the case that the user provided an appliance managed through an IPMI system, you will have the ability to insert the corresponding IP to IPMI in your system so you can connect to the sensor using IPMI.</para>
		<para> In the Network Settings menu select option<literal>IPMI Network configuration wizard</literal> entering the number <keycap>4.</keycap></para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ips-install/37.png"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>	
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Apply Changes</emphasis></para>
		<para> To finish the network configuration process, you must perform the action to  apply changes: <literal>apply</literal>, by selecting option<keycap>a.</keycap></para>
		<para>You can view the IPMI settings at any time by selecting the option <literal>info</literal> by entering the letter <keycap>i.</keycap></para>
		<para> To apply changes, the system will finish performing the configurations necessary to begin the registration of sensors.</para>	
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ips-install/36.png"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>	
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Sensor registration in Manager</title>
		<para>To complete the installation of the IPS sensors, the last step that must be performed is the <emphasis role="bold">Registration of sensors in Manager.</emphasis></para>
		<para>Until the registration has been completed, a message will be displayed indicating that the sensors are not yet registered in Manager.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ips-install/38.png"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>In the menu of registered sensors in Manager, the following are included:</para>
		<orderedlist numeration="arabic">
			<listitem>
				<para><literal>Hostame [rbsensor]:</literal> set name to sensor.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><literal>Set local time:</literal> set local time.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><literal>IP adress for rB Master Manager [127.0.0.1]:</literal>enter the IP Manager.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><literal>Register rB:</literal> registration of the sensors in the Sensor Manager / Manager. Until the registration process has been completed, the user will see a message displayed in red: <literal>(not registered yet)</literal></para>
			</listitem>
		</orderedlist>
		<section>
			<title>Set name to sensor (Hostname)</title>
			<para> Select the <literal>Hostname [rbsensor]</literal> from the Sensor Registration menu in Manager by entering the number <keycap>1.</keycap></para>
			<para> Then in the line <literal>Insert Hostname [rbsensor]:_</literal> write the name you want to give the sensor to be registered with the Manager. From this moment, this is the name displayed on the web when you access the list of IPS sensors.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ips-install/38.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			<note>
				<title>Note</title>
				<para>Remember to enter a different name for the sensor. Avoid using the name "Sensor", since it is the generic name used by the Manager and that could ultimately cause confusion.</para>
			</note>
			<warning>
				<title>Caution</title>
				<para>The system will ask you to verify that the chosen name is correct, then press <keycap>Enter</keycap></para>
				<para>To modify insert the letter <keycap>n</keycap></para>
				<para>the system will proceed to rename the sensor. To continue and to return to the redBorder menu setup system, <literal>Press a key to continue..._</literal></para>
			</warning>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ips-install/39.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>	
		</section>		
		<section>
			<title>Set local time</title>
			<para>Select the option <literal>Set local time</literal> found in the Sensor Registration settings in Manager by entering the number <keycap>2.</keycap></para>
			<para>This should  correspond to your selection you made in basic settings for the configuration process of IPS sensors.</para>
			<para> The system will show you two possible formats for inserting the date and time <literal>(Y=year):</literal></para>
			<itemizedlist mark="bullet">
				<listitem>
					<para><literal>[HH:mm]</literal> or <literal>[YYYY/MM/DD]</literal></para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><literal> [YYYY/MM/DD HH:mm]</literal></para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<para>Press <keycap>Enter</keycap> to continue the registration process. </para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ips-install/40.png"/>
			    </imageobject>
		    </mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Enter the IP of Master Manager</title>
			<para>Select the option <literal>IP adress for rB Master Manager [127.0.0.1]</literal> by entering the number <keycap>3.</keycap></para>
			<para>First, insert the IP address or domain name for the manager. The system will perform a series of checks to verify if the action can be accomplished. This process can take a few seconds.</para>
			<para>The system will synchronize the time service.</para>
			<para> Congratulations! Your system is prepared for sensor registration in Manager.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ips-install/41.png"/>
			    </imageobject>
		    </mediaobject>
		    <para>To continue, and return to the redBorder System Setup menu, <literal>Press a key to continue..._</literal></para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title> Sensor registration in Manager</title>
			<para>This is the last step for finishing the installation process of the redBorder IPS solution.</para>
			<para> From this point you can work directly from the IPS management application, in which your dashboard graphically displays all traffic events captured by the IPS sensors.</para>
			<para>In this application you can create reports, view events or set the rules of the Manager including actions.</para>
			<para><emphasis>Completion of the sensor registration process in Manager:</emphasis></para>
			<para> Here are the following steps to complete the sensor registration process in Manager:</para>
			<orderedlist numeration="arabic">
				<listitem>
					<para> Indicate whether you want to have a debug output: the system will prompt you with the question: <literal>Would you like to have a debug output?</literal> Select the default (No) by inserting the letter <keycap>N</keycap>.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Insert password: </emphasis>specify the password you entered the Manager.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold"> Time synchronization (automatic) between the Manager and sensors:</emphasis> this process may take a few seconds to complete.</para>
		        </listitem>
		       </orderedlist>
		       <mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ips-install/42.png"/>
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ips-install/43.png"/>
			        </imageobject>
		        </mediaobject>	
					<para>After performing these steps, the system will prompt you with a message that the sensor has been successfully registered. Sensor registered successfully with chef server</para>
					<para><literal> Sensor registered succesfully with chef server</literal></para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ips-install/44.png"/>
			            </imageobject>
		            </mediaobject>
			<warning>
				<title>Caution</title>
				<para>Do not rename the sensor or<emphasis>hostname</emphasis> once it has been registered. To make changes to the <emphasis>hostname </emphasis> it is necessary to undo the entire registration process and start over. </para>
			</warning>
			<para>To continue and return to the redBorder setup menu system, <literal>Press a key to continue..._</literal></para>
			<para>In the Sensor Registration menu in Manager, redBorder can verify that the sensor has been successfully <literal>(Registered).</literal></para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ips-install/45.png"/>
			    </imageobject>
		    </mediaobject>
		    <para> To exit the Sensor Registration wizard in Manager, select  <literal>quit</literal> by entering <keycap>q.</keycap></para>				
		</section>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Welcome to redBorder IPS</title>
		<para>Congratulations! You have successfully completed the installation of the redBorder IPS solution. From this point you can easily operate from the interface of the application.</para>
		<para>The next screen will display the sensors whose names match the given names in step <emphasis role="bold">Set name to sensor</emphasis> or <emphasis>(Hostname)</emphasis>.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ips-install/46.png"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
</chapter>
