<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE preface PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "manual.ent">
<!ENTITY PRODUCT "Documentation">
<!ENTITY BOOKID "manual">
<!ENTITY YEAR "2015">
<!ENTITY HOLDER "Eneo Tecnología S.L. |">
]>
<preface id="pref-manual-Preface">
  <title>Preface</title>
  <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="Common_Content/Conventions.xml"/>
  <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="Feedback.xml">
  </xi:include>
    <section>
		<title>Welcome to redBorder v.3- IPS Community: Generating community day-to-day</title>
		<para>Thank you very much for downloading rb_IPS_v.3-Community and welcome to the redBorder Community. </para>
        <para>We are pleased to introduce this new version of one of our star products: the intrusion prevention system (IPS), which together with the Flow, packets are found available on our website <emphasis>http://redborder.net/downloads-ips-community/</emphasis> for free download.</para>
        <para>All our products are Open Source, as one of the cornerstones of redBorder is to promote and generate community.</para>
        <para>Thanks to our community, we have the opportunity to constantly innovate and grow through the exchange of ideas, contributions and other uses developers do with our code.</para>
        <para>Therefore, first of all, we want to give thanks. Innovation is only possible if knowledge is shared. We grow with contributions from experts like you. We can test and validate our products internally and offer improvements to accommodate new needs.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
		<title>Knowing the Official Guide to Installing IPS redBorder v.3-Community</title>
		<para>This guide contains useful information that will help complete the installation of our redBorder IPS solution correctly. In this first chapter you will find some tips for using this guide. Read them carefully as they can be very useful when applying the concepts presented in this manual. The <emphasis>Official Guide to Installation redBorder v.3- IPS Community</emphasis> will provide the knowledge necessary for the installation of our redBorder IPS solution which consists of three steps:</para> 
        <itemizedlist mark="bullet">
			<listitem>
				<para>Configuration Manager</para>
			</listitem>
            <listitem>
				<para>Configuring IPS sensors</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
				<para>Sensor Registration in the Manager</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
       </section>
    <section>
		<title>How to use this manual</title>
		<para>This manual is designed for the implementation of the solution redBorder IPS Community version from the download file containing the installation ISO. This document is ideal for both users wishing to replace the old version, as well as those who are installing the redBorder IPS 3 Community for the first time.</para>
        <para>If you are already one of our users and have completed the installation of both the redBorder IPS and Manager at another time, you may go directly to <emphasis role="bold">Chapters 3 and 5 for installation of Manager and IPS Sensors.</emphasis></para>
        <section>
			<title>Requirements for the installation of redBorder IPS solution Community version</title>
            <para>The installation of  redBorder IPS solution Community Edition v.3 requires compliance with certain requirements to ensure correct settings and optimal functioning.</para>
			<para>There are two ways to do the installation of our redBorder IPS solution:</para>
			<itemizedlist mark="bullet">
				<listitem>
					<para>Local disk of your computer (Hardware).</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Structure of virtualization and Cloud.</para>
				</listitem>
		    </itemizedlist>
		    <note>
				<title>Note</title>
				<para>Cloud Solutions supported:</para>
				<itemizedlist mark="bullet">
					<listitem>
						<para>VMWare</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para> Open Stack</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Amazon Web Services (AWS)</para>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</note>
			<important>
			    <title>Important</title>
			    <para>redBorder Installation Requirements for the Manager on a physical computer:</para>
			    <para>Memory and Storage:<emphasis role= "bold"> 60GB hard drive and a minimum of 12GB of RAM.</emphasis> (This figure depends on the number of allocated sensors).</para>
			    <para><emphasis role= "bold"> At least one interface network for the Manager to operate.</emphasis></para>
		    </important>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Structure and operation of menus user interface Setup</title>
			<para><emphasis role="bold">Menu, submenu and command line</emphasis></para>
			<para>Menu Setup responds to a pattern repeated in almost all screens:</para>
			<itemizedlist mark="bullet">
				<listitem>
					<para>Menu</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Submenu</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Command Line</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ips-install/28.png"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
				<para><emphasis>Menu</emphasis></para>
				<para>Menu on the left side of the screen for a listing with the available options. To select any of them they must be entered in the line <literal>Selection</literal>, the number or letter corresponding to the option you want to choose.</para>
				<para><emphasis>Submenu</emphasis></para>
				<para> If you would like to perform different actions select submenu. It will appear on the right side of the screen.</para>
				<para><emphasis> Line command/Dial options</emphasis></para>
				<para>in the top margin, and separated from the menu and sub graph, find the area in which they should indicate selections on the line that contains <literal>Selection</literal> and enter commands or data requested to perform the appropriate actions. In this area the date and time of the system can be visualized (default UTC).</para>
			<section>
				<title>Selecting Options</title>
				<para><emphasis role="bold">Default options</emphasis></para>
				<para>In some cases of default options, the system will display a series of default options.</para>
				<para>If this is the answer to a particular question, the defined default option will be displayed in uppercase.</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ips-install/41.png"/>
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
				<para><emphasis role="bold">Options available in the redBorder installer menu</emphasis></para>
				<itemizedlist mark="bullet">
					<listitem>
						<para>Selecting default: Press <keycap>Enter.</keycap></para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para> Other options: enter the letter or command that corresponds.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Quit: when you want to exit a screen to return to the main menu select the <literal>quit</literal>, option by entering the letter <keycap>q.</keycap></para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Apply Changes: to save and apply the changes made, select <literal>apply</literal> by entering <keycap>a.</keycap></para>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						 <imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ips-install/35.png"/>
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
				<warning>
					<title>Caution</title>
					<para><literal>Need to "apply" to activate changes</literal></para>
					<para>If you see this message you must select the option <keycap>a</keycap>. Otherwise, the system will not store nor apply the changes.</para>
				</warning>
			</section>
		</section>
	</section>
</preface>
